[Music]
foreign
I have thoroughly enjoyed these last
days of Autumn and little did I know
that these fields of wild rye and
rosehip would all be buried under a
thick blanket of snow only a few days
after I took this walk
[Music]
foreign
thankfully I filled up my basket with
more than enough rose hips to last me
the winter and I look forward to many
nights of nutritious tea
I plan to remove and put aside a handful
in order to experiment with the recipe
making some sweet dough infused with
this fruity wild food
I loved an evening of experimentation
with these often overlooked Treasures
[Music]
foreign
I wanted to share something that has
often guided me as I go through the
chapters of my life and perhaps will
ReSound with you
let me ask you this
when you were your young child did you
ever spend time imagining all the things
you might be when you grow up perhaps it
was an artist an astronaut a singer
maybe you found yourself at a Crossroads
at some point when you were older should
I get married should I study this should
I live here or there
every time we made a decision we left
numerous potential life paths behind at
least for a while
[Music]
foreign
we may try different things live
different ways but by the end there's a
multitude of options left over that we
didn't have the time to discover if
you've ever found yourself wondering how
things could have been you have a
treasure of insight into who you are and
what you need
for example I've always had an interest
in people who have lived their lives in
solitude I also love plants and
sometimes wondered if I should have been
a scientist but right now I'm here with
the choices I made and while I'm
contented with those I still like to
revisit those unlived lives and wonder
what aspects of those possibilities
those what ifs I can imbue into my
present existence in order to enrich my
day
foreign
[Music]
as a lover of Botany I could take a
local class on plant identification with
an interest in mysticism I spent some
time in silent contemplation each day
you see while we cannot simultaneously
live each of those lives all at once and
explore their possibilities to the
fullest
there's often very little stopping us
from taking at least some small Gem of
inspiration from those other versions of
ourselves particularly if we're wistful
or lacking somehow in our present
[Music]
it has often helped me get through a
difficult time by adding a little
something into my day I let that other
life Inspire and teach me more about my
present
we aren't missing out we're allowing our
diverse interests and passions to live
with us even if it's in a small way
[Music]
foreign
right now I filmed Gathering the rose
hips and then only about a week later
just an enormous snowstorm hit us and my
mother I think had up to two feet of
snow at one point it has melted away a
little bit but there's still so much out
there and the valley is completely
transformed which is exciting and it
seems rather early to have this much
snow so autumn is definitely over which
is rather Bittersweet but winter is
always so enchanting a while ago I was
rather inspired to make a video on this
topic which I wasn't sure how people
would respond I I don't know if this is
a very relatable thing but what I do
know is that a lot of us often are
worried about making choices they can
seem so Monumental and critical and some
of which really are I know for a good
year or two after moving out here I
spent a lot of time wondering if I
should have stayed in university did I
make a mistake choosing life over here
you know even though those are questions
I'm now at peace with for quite a long
while I was very worried that I was not
making the right choices for myself and
and looking back on it I realized that
there wasn't necessarily a right or
wrong choice because each choice was
going to give me incredible
opportunities to grow and to learn even
though I'm not pursuing my degree and
don't have any plans to do that right
now I know that I still deeply enjoy
reading books and learning and reading a
paper now and then and exercising my
more critical mind and I can still have
that unlived life influenced me and
enriched my life right now even though
I'm not doing what I thought I would be
doing one way that I allowed that dream
that I did not pursue influenced me is
that I became a teacher at a preschool
for a while and that was an incredibly
rewarding experience and I still hope
someday to teach art classes that is a
long-term dream of mine there's so many
ways I can still mentor and teach even
though my life has taken a slightly
different direction thinking that way
makes me a little less afraid in regards
to choosing a life path because that
life path can take you in so many
different directions you can follow
multiple passions at the same time
depending on who we are we all have
limitations in what we can and cannot do
and that is why I think you know Finding
small ways to bring those other
interests into our lives can be really
rewarding I'll give one last example and
that is my own writing when I became an
adult I found it very difficult to get
my writing out there unless it was for
like a local magazine or something like
that I went to writers conferences and I
submitted my writing to agents all the
time and I would always get a very quick
response of we're not interested I think
one of the main criticisms of my writing
that I would submit usually in the form
of fiction novels was that my writing
style was too archaic and old-fashioned
that made sense because I did have a
huge passion for Victorian literature
and a lot of older literature that
definitely influenced my vocabulary and
my style of writing I heard so many
times over that that more archaic style
of writing just wouldn't be appealing to
many people so I started writing up
little scripts about you know thoughts
and Reflections on the day and life as a
quieter person and I started to share
them in the form of videos and it led me
to having this YouTube channel for a
long time those videos were a very small
part of my life as I was still working
full time at another job
but over time it surprised me and became
something much bigger so now I'm so glad
that I never completely gave up on my
interest in writing I wanted to say one
huge thank you to everyone who has
supported me through my Etsy shop thank
you so so much it really helps keep this
channel going I am just so grateful I
will be open to maybe three more weeks
at most but I do have to close for the
month of December because my little tiny
Town post office just gets a little bit
too busy and cannot handle any more
packages so I appreciate your support
right now and I will let you know a
little bit before I close thank you so
much and I hope you have a wonderful
week sending my love goodbye
foreign
[Music]